迈克 · 诺斯: 那么让我们深入研究一下泛型。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So let's dig into generics.
泛型参数化类型的方式与函数参数化值的方式相同。
Generics parameterize types in the same
way that functions parameterize values.
所以我们要讨论什么时候适合使用通用名。
So we're gonna talk about when
it's appropriate to use a generic.
通常类型参数的输入和输出。
The ins and
outs of type parameters in general.
以及如何约束类型参数
And how to constraint type parameters, for
例如，在一个函数中，你有你需要的东西来保证类型安全
example, within a function, you have what
you need in order to have type safety
内部的功能，外部世界也很满意。
within the function, and the outside
world is happy with things as well.
因为类型只是约束和
Cuz types are just constraints and
它们代表不同实体之间的合同。
they represent contracts
between various entities.
迈克 · 诺斯: 那么我们来看一下音符 / 5。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
we're gonna look at the notes/5.
如前所述，泛型参数化类型，如函数参数化值。
As I said, generics parameterize types
like functions parameterize values.
例如，如果我们有一个这样的函数,
For example,
if we had a function like this,
让我们假设它是用 JavaScript 编写的，对吗？
and let's pretend it's just
written in JavaScript, right?
在没有类型注释的情况下，此函数生成一个包装的值,
With no type annotation,
this function produces a wrapped value,
取决于我们给它什么，我们给它什么
and depending on what we feed it,
what we give it for
这将决定出来的东西的价值，对不对？
x, that will determine the value of
the thing that comes out, right?
我们可以把任何我们想要的东西放在那里
We can put whatever we want there, and
这个函数允许我们重复使用这段代码，不管我们想要包装一个字符串,
the function allows us to reuse this piece
of code, whether we want to wrap a string,
或者数字，或者在包装的值中包装的值,
or a number, or have a wrapped
value inside a wrapped value,
边界 x 是一个占位符。
the perimeter x is sort of
a placeholder that is used.
它允许重复使用这段代码。
And it allows to reuse this piece of code.
类似地，我们可以创建一个允许我们
Similarly, we can create
a type that allows us to
在这种情况下，在这些尖括号之间提供一个类型参数。
provide a type parameter in this case
X in between these angle brackets.
并且该类型参数将用作此属性值的类型。
And that type parameter will be used
as the type for this property value.
这里有一个例子，如果我传入字符串数组,
So here's an example,
if I pass in string array,
这就像把一个参数传递给一个函数，对吗？
this is just like passing
an argument to a function, right?
但是我将一个类型传递给泛型类型。
But I'm passing a type to a generic type.
迈克 · 诺斯: 因为有这样的工具提示,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
because of the tool tips like,
迈克 · 诺斯: 这是正确的，但是
&gt;&gt; Mike North: This is correct, but
我更感兴趣的是我能用这个东西做什么。
I'm more interested in what
I can do with this thing.
如果我们看看 val.value,
If we look at val.value,
我们可以看到它是一个字符串数组。
we can see that it is a string array.
迈克 · 诺斯: 就像你在这里看到的那样。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: As you
can see right over here.
迈克 · 诺斯: 如果我们把它改成一个字符串,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: If we were to change
this and make it just a string, well,
我们会得到一个类型错误，我们必须使这是一个字符串。
we would get a type error here,
we'd have to make this a string.
Mike North: 现在，值的类型是 string。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And now,
the type of value is string.
对不起，它总是消失，我对我的鼠标太过热心了。
Sorry, it keeps disappearing,
I'm being overzealous with my mouse.
但是希望你们可以看到，我们我们有点填补了一个空白或者
But hopefully you can see here,
we're we're sort of filling in a blank or
提供一个类型，然后将其合并到 WrappedValue 的内容中。
providing a type that is then incorporated
into what WrappedValue shakes out to be.
Mike North: 所以你可以随心所欲地命名这些类型参数。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So you can name these
type parameters whatever you want.
我可以做这个，Mike North: Name 函数键。
I can make this,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Name function keys.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我可以让它成为主唱,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: I can
make it FrontEndMasters,
就像你可以随意命名函数参数一样。
just like you can name function
params whatever you want.
这完全是一个本地名字，指的是所有能接触到这个的东西
That's completely a local name to
everything that has access to this
类型 param，也就是某种意义上的，把它看作一个闭包。
type param, which is just sort of, think
of it like the same idea as a closure.
你有一个作用域这是一个局部变量,
Right, you have a scope, and
this is a local variable,
这几乎就像传递给函数的参数。
it's almost like an argument
passed to a function.
该参数的名称只在该函数中有意义。
The name of that argument only
has meaning within that function.
迈克 · 诺斯: 你们会经常看到的这个会议，就是从这里开始的
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So the convention,
which you'll see a lot, is to start with
大写字母 t，并使用大写字母如 t，u，v，或 s，或 r。
the capital letter T, and use capital
letters like T, U, V, or S, or R.
这是从使用模板参数的 c + + 继承而来的
This a carryover from C++
which uses template parameters
基本上它们在概念上是一致的。
which basically they're
conceptually identical to this.
这就是为什么你会看到大量的打字稿编码,
So that's why you'll see
a lot of TypeScript coding,
包括我的例子，他们只会使用大写字母 t。
including my examples,
they'll just use the capital letter T.
这就好比说这个函数取 x 和
But that's just like saying
this function takes x and
我们可以给它起任何我们想要的名字。
y as arguments, and
we can name this whatever we want.
Mike North: 如果我们使用数组过滤器,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So if we were using
something like array filter,
我们可以输入一个函数，这个函数可以根据
we could type a function that would
appropriately filter based on
这个数组中可能存在的东西的类型，对吗？
the types of things that might
be in this array, right?
如果我们通过一个字符串数组进行过滤，这样我们就可以删除任何空字符串
If we were filtering through an array of
strings, so that we could remove any empty
字符串，我们希望接受它作为过滤函数,
string we found, we'd want to
accept as our filtering function,
我们希望用一个字符串作为参数，然后返回一个布尔值。
we'd want that to take a string as
an argument and to return a boolean.
事实上，如果我们有一个包含字符串的数组,
And in fact, that is what happens,
if we had an array containing strings,
. filter () ，Mike North: And
.filter(),
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And
我们开始实现我们的回调，迈克 · 诺斯: 我们开始吧
we start to implement our callback,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Let's
假设这是一个总是通过的过滤器，结果 x 的值是一个字符串。
say it's a filter that always passes,
it turns out x has a value of a string.
迈克 · 诺斯: 对吧？ 这正是我们想要的。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Right?
That's just what we want.
如果我们有一个命名函数
If we had a named function
that was designed
致，迈克 · 诺斯: 名字
to,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Named
这样的功能，迈克诺斯: 这只是想接收
function like this,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: That only wanted to receive
数字，我们绝对希望这样说，这里有一个错位。
numbers, we would absolutely want this
to say, there's a misalignment here.
你的函数被设计成接受数字,
Your function's designed to take numbers,
我需要一个可以带字符串的。
I need one that's
designed to take strings.
所以这将是一个适当的类型，使用一个通用类型，将允许我们排序
So this would be an appropriate type using
a generic that would allow us to sort of
填空，你过滤的实体类型是什么？
fill in the blank, what is the type
of the entity you're filtering for?
迈克 · 诺斯: 这里有一个我们使用这种通用类型传入的例子
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So here's an example of
us using this generic type of passing in
字符串作为类型参数，所以这个 t 将变成一个字符串。
string as the type parameter, so
this T will turn into a string.
现在我们可以看到，val 是一个字符串
And we can see that now,
val is a string, and
我们正在检查 val 的类型是否是字符串。
we're checking to see if
the type of val is a string.
这一切看起来都很棒，对吧？
This all looks great to me, right?
运行时的东西，对不起，运行时的东西看起来
The runtime stuff, this, sorry,
that runtime stuff looks
就像我要检查是否有一个字符串或
exactly like what I would want
to check if there's a string or
不是，这应该是一个字符串。
not, and this in fact should be a string.
Mike North: 如果我们试图解析错误的参数，很明显我们会得到一个错误,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: If we try to parse in the
wrong argument, obviously we get an error,
否则，如果是正确的类型，我们就没问题。
otherwise if it's the right type,
we get OK.